<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Path of the Giant</name>
    <description>Path of the Giant (Unearthed Arcana)</description>
    <author url="https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/giant-options-barbarians-and-druids">Unearthed Arcana - Giant Options for Barbarians and Druids</author>
    <update version="1.0.0">
      <file name="barbarian-giant.xml" url="" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <!-- Path of the Giant -->
  <element name="Path of the Giant" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_PATH_OF_THE_GIANT">
    <supports>Primal Path</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Barbarians who follow the Path of the Giant draw on the primal forces of the giants, channeling their elemental might and embracing the vast strength and presence of these ancient beings.</p>
      <div element="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_GIANT'S_POWER" />
      <div element="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_GIANT'S_HAVOC" />
      <div element="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CLEAVER" />
      <div element="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_MIGHT_OF_THE_GIANT" />
      <div element="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_RUNE_OF_THE_GIANT" />
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_GIANT'S_POWER" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_GIANT'S_HAVOC" level="3" /> 
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CLEAVER" level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_MIGHT_OF_THE_GIANT" level="10" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_RUNE_OF_THE_GIANT" level="14" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <!-- Giant’s Power -->
  <element name="Giant’s Power" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_GIANT'S_POWER">
    <description>
      <p>When you choose this path, you learn to speak, read, and write Giant or one other language of your choice if you already know Giant. Additionally, you learn a cantrip of your choice: either <i>druidcraft</i> or <i>thaumaturgy</i>. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Learn Giant (or one language of choice if already known). Learn Druidcraft or Thaumaturgy (Wisdom is your spellcasting ability).</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Giant’s Havoc -->
  <element name="Giant’s Havoc" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_GIANT'S_HAVOC">
    <description>
      <p>Your rages pull strength from the primal might of giants, transforming you into a hulking force of destruction. While raging, you gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Crushing Throw.</b> When you make a successful ranged attack with a thrown weapon using Strength, you can add your Rage Damage bonus to the attack’s damage roll.</li>
        <li><b>Giant Stature.</b> Your reach increases by 5 feet, and if you are smaller than Large, you become Large, along with anything you are wearing. If there isn’t enough room for you to increase your size, your size doesn’t change.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>While raging: add Rage Damage to thrown weapon attacks (Str). Your reach increases by 5 ft, and you become Large unless space prevents it.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Elemental Cleaver -->
  <element name="Elemental Cleaver" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CLEAVER">
    <description>
      <p>At 6th level, your rage channels elemental power. When you enter your rage, you can imbue one weapon you’re holding with elemental energy of your choice: acid, cold, fire, thunder, or lightning. While you’re raging, the weapon deals an extra 1d6 of the chosen damage type. You can also throw the weapon (range 20/60 ft.), and it returns to your hand after the attack.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you rage, imbue a weapon with acid, cold, fire, thunder, or lightning. It deals +1d6 of that type and returns when thrown (range 20/60).</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Might of the Giant -->
  <element name="Might of the Giant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_MIGHT_OF_THE_GIANT">
    <description>
      <p>At 10th level, you have grown in physical might and presence. Your size becomes Large if it was Medium or smaller, and your reach increases by 5 feet. You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Your size becomes Large; your reach increases by 5 ft. Advantage on Strength checks and saves.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Rune of the Giant -->
  <element name="Rune of the Giant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Giant Options" id="ID_UA_GIANT_OPTIONS_FEATURE_RUNE_OF_THE_GIANT">
    <description>
      <p>At 14th level, you learn to call upon the runes of giant magic to augment your might. As a bonus action, you can invoke a rune for 1 minute, gaining one of the following benefits of your choice: resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage; an additional 5-foot increase to your reach; or advantage on attack rolls. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier per long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{modifier:constitution}}/Long Rest">
      <description>Invoke a rune for 1 minute: gain resistance to bludgeoning/piercing/slashing, +5 ft. reach, or advantage on attacks. Use {{modifier:constitution}}/Long Rest.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>
