<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>

  <!-- Subclass Definition -->
  <element name="Path of the Giant" type="Archetype" id="ID_GIANT_PATH_OF_THE_GIANT">
    <description>
      <p>Those who follow the Path of the Giant embody the primal strength and elemental power of the giants.</p>
    </description>
    <supports>Primal Path</supports>
    <set name="class">Barbarian</set>
    <grants>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_GIANTS_POWER" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_GIANTS_HAVOC" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_ELEMENTAL_CLEAVER" level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_MIGHTY_IMPEL" level="10" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_DEMIURGIC_COLOSSUS" level="14" />
    </grants>
  </element>

  <!-- Level 3: Giant's Power -->
  <element name="Giant's Power" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_GIANTS_POWER">
    <description>
      <p>When you choose this path, you learn to speak, read, and write Giant or one other language of your choice if you already know Giant. Additionally, you learn a cantrip of your choice: either <i>druidcraft</i> or <i>thaumaturgy</i>. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Learn Giant (or one other language). Gain the <i>druidcraft</i> or <i>thaumaturgy</i> cantrip (Wisdom as spellcasting ability).</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Level 3: Giant's Havoc -->
  <element name="Giant's Havoc" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_GIANTS_HAVOC">
    <description>
      <p>Your rages pull strength from the primal might of giants, transforming you into a hulking force of destruction. While raging, you gain the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li><b>Crushing Throw:</b> When you make a successful ranged attack with a thrown weapon using Strength, you can add your Rage Damage bonus to the attack’s damage roll.</li>
        <li><b>Giant Stature:</b> Your reach increases by 5 feet, and if you are smaller than Large, you become Large, along with anything you are wearing. If there isn’t enough room for you to increase your size, your size doesn’t change.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>While raging: +5 ft reach, become Large, and add Rage Damage to thrown weapon attacks.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Level 6: Elemental Cleaver -->
  <element name="Elemental Cleaver" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_ELEMENTAL_CLEAVER">
    <description>
      <p>Your bond with the elemental might of giants grows, and you learn to infuse weapons with primordial energy.</p>
      <p>When you enter your rage, you can choose one weapon that you are holding and infuse it with one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, thunder, or lightning. While you wield the infused weapon during your rage, the weapon’s damage type changes to the chosen type, it deals an extra 1d6 damage of the chosen type when it hits, and it gains the thrown property (range 20/60). If you throw the weapon, it reappears in your hand the instant after it hits or misses a target. The infused weapon’s benefits are suppressed while a creature other than you wields it.</p>
      <p>While raging and holding the infused weapon, you can use a bonus action to change the weapon’s current damage type to another from the list above.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you rage, infuse one weapon with acid, cold, fire, thunder, or lightning. It deals +1d6 of that type, gains thrown (20/60), and returns when thrown. Bonus Action: change type.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Level 10: Mighty Impel -->
  <element name="Mighty Impel" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_MIGHTY_IMPEL">
    <description>
      <p>Your connection to giant strength allows you to hurl both allies and enemies on the battlefield. As a bonus action while raging, you can choose one Medium or smaller creature within your reach and move it to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of yourself. An unwilling creature must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) to avoid the effect.</p>
      <p>If, at the end of this movement, the thrown creature isn’t on a surface or liquid that can support it, the creature falls, taking damage as normal and landing prone.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Bonus Action while raging: throw a Medium or smaller creature up to 30 ft. Str save (DC 8 + PB + STR) negates. If unsupported, it falls prone and takes fall damage.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Level 14: Demiurgic Colossus -->
  <element name="Demiurgic Colossus" type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_GIANT_DEMIURGIC_COLOSSUS">
    <description>
      <p>The primordial power of your rage intensifies. When you rage, your reach increases by 10 feet, your size can increase to Large or Huge (your choice), and you can use your Mighty Impel to move creatures that are Large or smaller.</p>
      <p>In addition, the extra damage dealt by your Elemental Cleaver feature increases to 2d6.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you rage: reach +10 ft, size becomes Large or Huge, can throw Large or smaller creatures with Mighty Impel, and Elemental Cleaver deals +2d6.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

</elements>
